<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<eml:eml xmlns:eml="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="eml://ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.1.1 http://rs.gbif.org/schema/eml-gbif-profile/1.2/eml.xsd"
packageId="f88bbba9-41d1-4cc8-b19f-94d50b58cada"  system="http://gbif.org" scope="system"
xml:lang="en">

    <dataset>
            <alternateIdentifier>10.15468/bbac62</alternateIdentifier>
                <alternateIdentifier>https://macroalgae.org/portal/collections/misc/collprofiles.php?collid=3</alternateIdentifier>
        <title>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Herbarium; Max &amp; Fran Hommersand Algae Herbarium: Algae</title>
            <creator>
<organizationName>Macroalgal Herbarium Portal</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>Chris.Neefus@unh.edu</electronicMailAddress><onlineUrl>https://macroalgae.org/portal/index.php</onlineUrl>            </creator>
            <metadataProvider>
<organizationName>Macroalgal Herbarium Portal</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>Chris.Neefus@unh.edu</electronicMailAddress><onlineUrl>https://macroalgae.org/portal/index.php</onlineUrl>            </metadataProvider>
            <associatedParty>
            <individualName>
<givenName>Carol Ann</givenName>                    <surName>McCormick</surName>
            </individualName>
<positionName>Curatrix</positionName><electronicMailAddress>mccormick@unc.edu</electronicMailAddress>            <userId directory="https://orcid.org/">0000-0003-3785-8433</userId>
            <role>CONTENT_PROVIDER</role>
            </associatedParty>
            <associatedParty>
            <individualName>
<givenName>Alan S.</givenName>                    <surName>Weakley</surName>
            </individualName>
<positionName>Director</positionName><electronicMailAddress>weakley@unc.edu</electronicMailAddress>            <role>CONTENT_PROVIDER</role>
            </associatedParty>
            <associatedParty>
            <individualName>
<givenName>Paul</givenName>                    <surName>Gabrielson</surName>
            </individualName>
<positionName>Macroalgae Curator</positionName><electronicMailAddress>drseaweed@hotmail.com</electronicMailAddress>            <role>CONTENT_PROVIDER</role>
            </associatedParty>
            <pubDate>
                2023-04-03
            </pubDate>
        <language>ENGLISH</language>
            <abstract>
                    <para>The Max &amp;amp; Fran Hommersand Algae Herbarium is curated by the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Herbarium (NCU).  Note that algae collected before 1995 by Hommersand were placed in formalin. Gabrielson&amp;#39;s non-coralline specimens are a mix; if pressed fresh this is noted on the specimen label. Gabrielson&amp;#39;s coralline specimens were not put in formalin unless noted on the label. NCU also curates vascular plants, lichens, fungi, bryophytes, &amp;amp; plant fossils. NCU, located in the center of the UNC-CH campus, welcomes visitors &amp;amp; researchers; contact Curator for information on hours &amp;amp; parking. STATEMENT ON OFFENSIVE CONTENT ON SPECIMEN LABELS: Collection records at NCU may contain language that reflects historical place or taxon names in an original form that is no longer acceptable or appropriate in an inclusive environment. Because NCU preserves data in their original form to retain authenticity and facilitate research, we have chosen to facilitate conversations and are committed to address the problem of racial, derogatory and demeaning language that may be found in our database. Insensitive or offensive language is not condoned by NCU. We recognize the land and sovereignty of Native &amp;amp; Indigenous nations in Chapel Hill, in North Carolina, in North America, and across the world. The North Carolina Botanical Garden and the North Carolina Botanical Garden Foundation acknowledge that the story told about the history of the land we steward has been incomplete. These lands were home to multiple tribes &amp;amp; the ancestors of the Occaneechi Band of the Saponi Nation persist locally to this day. We recognize that at least one of the adjacent lands we steward, Mason Farm Biological Reserve, was first cleared, cultivated, &amp;amp; worked by Native Americans &amp;amp; later by African enslaved people. We invite you to reflect on our individual &amp;amp; community roles in knowing important &amp;amp; untold stories about the land we each steward.</para>
            </abstract>
            <intellectualRights>
                    <para>This work is licensed under a <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/legalcode"><citetitle>Creative Commons Attribution Non Commercial (CC-BY-NC) 4.0 License</citetitle></ulink>.</para>
            </intellectualRights>
            <contact>
<organizationName>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Herbarium; Max &amp; Fran Hommersand Algae Herbarium: Algae</organizationName><electronicMailAddress>mccormick@unc.edu</electronicMailAddress><onlineUrl>https://ncbg.unc.edu/research/unc-herbarium/</onlineUrl>            <userId directory="https://orcid.org/">0000-0003-3785-8433</userId>
            </contact>

    </dataset>

    <additionalMetadata>
        <metadata>
            <gbif>
                <dateStamp>2023-04-13T10:32:02Z</dateStamp>
                <citation>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Herbarium (NCU) (2023). University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill Herbarium; Max &amp; Fran Hommersand Algae Herbarium: Algae. Occurrence dataset https://doi.org/10.15468/bbac62 accessed via GBIF.org on 2023-04-13.</citation>
            </gbif>
        </metadata>
    </additionalMetadata>

</eml:eml>
